Guide to the Jewish Labor Committee Photographs PHOTOS 048
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series I: General JLC Activities
  - Subseries F: JLC Staff, Branches, Chapters, Divisions, Committees
    Includes group portraits of JLC staff and photographs related to the work of the organization's National Executive Committee, Legislative Committee, Educators' Chapter, Women's Division, and local chapters.
    - JLC Staff, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - National Executive Committee, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Legislative Committee, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Membership Division, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Educators' Chapter, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Workmen's Circle branches, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Women's Division, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - California Chapter, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Illinois Chapter, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Maryland Chapter, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Minnesota Chapter, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Missouri Chapter, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - New England Chapter, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Ohio Chapter, undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Oregon Chapter, undated (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Pennsylvania Chapter, undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Washington, D.C. Chapter, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Canada Chapter, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Chicago Chapter, 1956, 1965, 1971, 1973, 1975 (Box 10)
    - Philadelphia Chapter, 1972-1975 (Box 10)
    - Los Angeles Chapter, 1974 (Box 10)
    - Field Offices: Individual and Group Portraits, circa 1960-1989 (Box 10)
    - Workmen's Circle, undated (Box 10)
  - Subseries G: Miscellaneous
    Contains photographs of unidentified events and of subjects only indirectly related to the activities of the JLC. It includes a group of images of synagogues and other Jewish community buildings in the Netherlands.
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - AFL-CIO Convention Backdrop, 1955-1956 (Box 10)
    - C.I.O. Summer School, 1946 (Box 10)
    - Jewish Labor Bund, undated (Box 10)
- Series II: Personalities
  Contains portraits of individuals connected with the JLC.
  - Subseries A: JLC Leadership
    Officials and photographs of unidentified events that prominently feature them.
    - David Dubinsky, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Benjamin Gebiner, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Adolph Held, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Emanuel Muravchik, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Michael S. Perry, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Benjamin Tabachinsky, undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Baruch Charney Vladeck, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Charles Zimmerman, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Jacob Zukerman, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Subseries B: General
    Consists of portraits of identified individuals alphabetically arranged and group portraits of prominent personalities at unidentified events. The subseries also contains a folder of unidentified portraits and an album of photographs devoted to the life and career of Leon Blum.
    (See also the INDEX TO PERSONALITIES for a partial cross-reference to more photographs of these and other prominent individuals that appear elsewhere in the collection.)
    - Leon Blum: Album of photographs, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Leon Blum Luncheon, April 13, 1946, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - A-C Irving Abramson Fritz Adler Frank Z. Atran Herman Becker Hayyim Nachman Bialik Ella Bogval Irving Brown Abraham Cahan Nathan Chanin Leo M. Cherne Jay Chapman Gerald Coleman, undated (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - D-G Louis de Brouckere Leon Dennen [Denenberg] Richardson Dilworth Oscar Ewing Arthur Goldberg Paul Goldman Samuel Gompers Patrick Gorman William Green Greppi (Mayor of Milan) Murray Gross, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - H-K Moshe Haar W. Averell Harriman Myra Hess Sidney Hillman Louis Hollander Samuel P. Hugh, Jr. (?) Hubert Humphrey Professor Kaplan John F. Kennedy Dimitri Klepinin, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - L-P Victor Larock Louis Levy Herve L'Heureux Itzik Manger Michael Mann George Meany Benjamin and Vladka Meed Bella Meiksin Lord Melchett Walter Mondale Max Mont Pauline M. Newman Paul Olberg Molly Picon, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - R-Z Avraham Reisen Emmanuel Ringelblum Franklin Delano Roosevelt Kurt Schumacher Senator Lewis Schwellenbach Benzel Sokiranski Congressman William P. Stratton Maurice Tobin Paul Tyson Bentsl Tsolevitsh James A. Wechsler Uriel Weinreich Chaim Weizmann Roy Wilkins Alex Wollod William Wolpert Leonard Woodcock Assistant Secretary of Labor Ralph Wright B. Zivion, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Groups Some Individuals represented in this file: Raphael Abramowitsch Robert Abram Luigi Antonini Shelley Appleton Adolf Arnaut Nathan Bar Yaacov Gregory Bardacke Joseph Baskin Mr. and Mrs. Chaim Bass Sh. Bikel Israel Breslow Yudl Borenstein Nathan Chanin Martin Cohen David Dubinsky Levi Eshkol Y. Feinberg David Gingold Arturo Giovanitti Joseph Glickson I.H. Goldberg Chaim Grade John Green William Green Murray Gross Fritz Heine Adolph Held Philip Heller Hershkowitz Louis Hollander Carl Jennings Morris Jushewitz I. Knapp J. Knox Jules Kolodny Walter Kushenbaum J. Landis Herbert S. Lehmann John Lewis Marx Lewis John V. Lindsay Michael Mann Bishop McConnell George Meany Vladka Meed Golda Meir Melnick Isaiah Minkoff Joseph Mlotek Emanuel Muravchik Morris Novick Jacob Pat Emmanuel Patt Louis Pincus Jacob S. Potofsky Chaim Pupko Steven Remson Alex Rose Devorah Rosenblum Jack Rubinstein Moshe Rubinstein Bayard Rustin Jacob Schlitt Edward Schneider Y. Schwartz Walter Seifert Zalman Shazar Dr. Silberberg Don Slaiman Leon Stern William Stern Stolarsky Benjamin Tabachinsky Norman Thomas President Harry S. Truman Y. Tyberg Liv Ullman Irving Vogel Mayor Robert F. Wagner, Jr. M. Waldman Richard Walsh Simon Weber William Wolpert Jerry Wurf Charles Zimmerman Jacob Zukerman, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Rotman, Sara, undated (Box 10)
    - Berger, Veil, undated (Box 10)
    - Herszkowicz, Jankiel, undated (Box 10)
- Series III: Aid to Children
  Documents JLC's child relief activities in Europe and Israel immediately following the end of World War II. The bulk of the photographs are of JLC-supported orphanages and children's homes in France.
  - Subseries A: Child Adoption Program, United States.
    Portrays the support of United States trade unions and Workmen's Circle branches for JLC's overseas children's homes. The bulk of the photographs are of union members inside garment factories and members of Workmen's Circle branches handing over donation checks to JLC representatives. There also several albums of portraits of children sponsored by specific unions. (See also Series IV and individual child portraits in case files.)
    - Child Adoption Program -- Participating unions and other labor groups, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Child Adoption Program -- Participating Workmen's Circle branches, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Child Adoption Program -- Workmen's Circle, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Child Adoption Program -- For children in Belgium, 1948-1949 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Children Adopted by Individuals, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Album of photos of children adopted by the Out of Town Cloak Department of the ILGWU, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Album of photos of children adopted by the United Cloak, Suit, Infants and Children's Coat Operators and Sample Makers Union, ILGWU, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Album of photos of children adopted by Cloak Joint Board, undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Album of photos of children adopted by unidentified garment workers' union, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Montages of children's portraits used for publicity materials, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Children brought to the United States, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Rosenberg, Klod Case File, 1949 (Box 10)
  - Subseries B: European Orphanages and Children's Homes and Other Child Aid Activities (Excluding France)
    Contains photographs of JLC-sponsored summer camps, orphanages and children's homes in Belgium, England, Italy, and Poland.
    - Left Poale Zion children's summer camps in the Brussels area, Belgium, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Children's summer camps at Braine le Compte and other places in the Brussels area, Belgium, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Workmen's Circle summer camp at Midelkerk, Belgium, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - La Hilf summer camp, Belgium, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Children in dramatic performances, Friends of Children Society, Brussels, Belgium, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Children in dramatic performances, S. Mendelson School, Brussels, Belgium, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Children at meals and in dramatic performances, Y. L. Peretz School, Brussels, Belgium, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Children in unidentified dramatic performances and miscellaneous, Belgium, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Bundist Shmider fun nayem lebn [Forgers of New Life] summer camp, England, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - French members of the Bundist youth group, SKIF, on a visit to England, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - JLC delegation bringing aid packages to the Associazione Nazionale enti Assistenza for poor Italian children, Milan, Italy, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - JLC delegation visiting child aid project in Rome, Italy, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Orphanage or summer camp, Selvino, Italy, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous, Italy, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Children's homes, orphanages, and summer camps, Poland, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Subseries C: Children's Homes and Orphanages and Other Child Aid Projects in France
    Documents JLC-sponsored children's homes in France such as the Nahum Aronson Home, the Shlomo Mendelson Home, the Emanuel Ringelblum Home, the B. Charney Vladeck sanatorium, the Morris Sigman Home and others. The subseries also contains images of day nurseries and of the activities of the Bundist youth groups, SKIF and Tsukunft, in France.
    - Nahum Aronson Home, Andelys, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Nahum Aronson Home, Andelys (album), undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Nahum Aronson Home, Andelys (album), undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - La Colonie Scolaire homes and programs, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - IKA Home, Corvol-1`Orgueilleux, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Bertha Mehring Nursery, Paris, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - S. Mendelson Home, Le Mans, #1, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - S. Mendelson Home, Le Mans, #2, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - S. Mendelson Home, Le Mans, #3, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - S. Mendelson Home, Le Mans -- field trip to Paris, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - S. Mendelson Home, Le Mans (album), undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - S. Mendelson Home, Le Mans (album), undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - S. Mendelson Home, Le Mans (album), undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - S. Mendelson Home, Le Mans (album fragments), undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Maison d'enfants d'Ophem, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Physical Culture Center, Gournay sur Marne, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Emmanuel Ringelblum Home, Paris, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - B. Charney Vladeck Home, Brunoy, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - B. Charney Vladeck Home, Brunoy, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - B. Charney Vladeck Home, Brunoy, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Morris Sigman Home, Paris, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous day nurseries, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - SKIF and Tsukunft groups, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Children Group Portraits: France, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Individual Children: France, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Children, miscellaneous, undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Children, miscellaneous, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Series IV: Photograph Albums and Oversized Photographs
  - Albums of photographs of individual children (and information relating to them) sponsored by United States trade unions Photocopies of Jewish Daily Forward photo essays on Child Adoption, undated (Box 8)
  - Albums of photographs of individual children (and information relating to them) sponsored by United States trade unions, and one oversized album of Left Poale Zion housing and other construction projects in Israel., undated (Box 9)
  - Oversized photographs (mostly panoramic views of JLC meetings and banquets)., undated (Drawer FFC: 6-6)
- Series V: Unprocessed
  - Miscellaneous (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 12)
  - Photographs of children, from "children's files", undated (Box 12)
  - George Meany with others, 1984 (Box 12)